<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: news | PCS Quorum Branch]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-17T10:59:13+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PCS Quorum]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Important news for FTA members]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/12/17/important-news-for-fta-members/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-17T09:02:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/12/17/important-news-for-fta-members</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have received some updates on negotiations from PCS regarding the future of our members on FTA contracts. If you are on a FTA contract we would encourage you to have a look and share with your colleagues. Updates will also be shared in the workplace as we receive them.</p>

<blockquote><p>PCS remains fundamentally opposed to HMRC's proposal not to renew the majority of FTA contracts when they are due to end in March 2014.</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>Following negotiations the department has announced plans to offer more than 1,000 FTA workers a further extension to their contracts.</p>

<p>While the exact details are yet to be worked out, PCS negotiators have had further meetings with the employer and will issue further information shortly, in order to keep FTA members informed.</p>

<p>PCS still insist that further job cuts are unnecessary, and will do everything possible to save the jobs of our FTA members.</p>

<p>Further information can be found <a href="http://www.pcs.org.uk/en/revenue_and_customs_group/latest-news/index.cfm">on the PCS website</a>.</p>

<p>If you have any questions please contact one of our reps and we will ensure your concerns are escalated.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Latest news in Personal Tax]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/11/14/latest-news-in-personal-tax/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-14T11:36:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/11/14/latest-news-in-personal-tax</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have recently issued a short newsletter which you should have had dropped on your desk, or will shortly. There are some updates from PCS you may not have seen yet, and we would encourage all members to stay up to date on current developments as they will affect all of us.</p>

<h2>Successful negotiation of increased annual leave allocations</h2>

<p>We would encourage all members to <a href="http://www.pcs.org.uk/en/revenue_and_customs_group/latest-news/index.cfm/successfull-negotiation-of-increased-annual-leave-allocations-in-personal-tax-operations-in-january-february-and-march">read this update on annual leave allocations</a> as it also includes information on a package of measure PCS are negotiating with management to reduce some of the pressures members are experiencing at work.</p>

<p>In a few weeks we would expect to see a detailed proposal on these measures from management, and would expect to give all members the chance to express their views on these measures in a consultative ballot.</p>

<h2>Branch update</h2>

<p>Our branch reps are continuing to represent members from Quorum as usual. Details on contacting us have been desk dropped over the last few days but you can contact any of our reps from the list <a href="/about">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Office move nearly here]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/08/29/office-move-nearly-here/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-29T12:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/08/29/office-move-nearly-here</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following the office move, members from Quorum Branch can still contact their current branch reps for any advice or cases. We will give you further information once things have been confirmed, but for the moment it will be business as usual for any union advice you may need.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Learning at Work Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/08/29/final-learning-at-work-day/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-29T11:43:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/08/29/final-learning-at-work-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Next Wednesday 4 September is the final Learning at Work Day for our branch. The event will be held throughout the day in Quorum 4, and time will be allocated for everyone to attend and have a look at the stalls. We have a number of learning providers coming along, as well as other companies.</p>

<p>We hope to make this, our last event a big success before the office closes. Our learning team look forward to seeing you all on the day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nominations close in branch elections]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/02/08/nominations-close-in-branch-elections/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T09:40:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/02/08/nominations-close-in-branch-elections</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nominations were requested in January to fill positions in our annual branch elections, and to elect delegates from our branch to the PCS Conference in May. Nominations have now closed, and all positions were filled uncontested. We would like to welcome all newcomers to the branch. You can <a href="/about">see a full list of your reps on the About page</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
