<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: news | PCS Quorum Branch]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-29T11:34:10+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PCS Quorum]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[January Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/01/10/january-update/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-10T07:23:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2013/01/10/january-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There has been a lot of activity in the group around Christmas, much of which is relevant to us at Quorum.</p>

<h2>Extension to FTA Contracts &amp; Increase in Hours for Permanent Staff</h2>

<p>It was announced in December that FTAs in our location who are eligible will have their contracts extended to September 2013. This couldn't have been done without the union's push to convert TFTAs to FTAs, and was very welcome news before Christmas.</p>

<p>PCS will continue to argue the case for Personal Tax to be staffed by permanent, public sector workers and therefore we will continue to push for permanent jobs for our FTA members and for an end to the job cuts in Personal Tax.</p>

<h2>Public sector jobs to replace private in Lillyhall CC</h2>

<p>Lillyhall is one of the two locations that HMRC is trialling the involvement of private sector providers in our contact centres, so it was good to learn that HMRC intend to recruit 70 new FTAs in an attempt to improve performance. It is hoped that many of the workers currently employed by Sitel will be able to secure employment with HMRC.</p>

<h2>Building capacity trial - PCS response to HMRC's 9 month update</h2>

<p>PCS have <a href="http://www.pcs.org.uk/en/revenue_and_customs_group/latest-news/index.cfm/id/889FC336-EE51-4873-A9F6CBD7E1AACDB8">published their response to HMRC trials here</a>. They will continue to oppose the use of private sector companies in our contact centres. Further information will be available when the evaluation finishes in the Spring.</p>

<p>This will be a difficult year for many of us in Quorum, but your local branch will be here as ever to support and advise you. Branch nominations are open now for our last elections in this office so if you have ever considered being more involved now is the time.</p>

<p>We would also like to invite all members to attend our Annual General Meeting next month. These are very well attended and give you the opportunity to be involved in the decision making process of your union. There will also be a question and answer session, so please take the opportunity to ask any questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decisions made on national campaign]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2012/12/14/decisions-made-on-national-campaign/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T11:49:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2012/12/14/decisions-made-on-national-campaign</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The union has issued a branch briefing reporting back from a recent meeting of the National Executive Committee detailing decisions made on the ongoing campaign.</p>

<p>The NEC has agreed plans for a campaign focusing on pay and conditions. They will be writing to employers setting out our demands and calling for negotiations.</p>

<p>The government's reponse will be assessed in January, with a national ballot for a programme of industrial action to follow if the employer's response is unsatisfactory.</p>

<p>Further details <a href="http://www.pcs.org.uk/en/news_and_events/pcs_comment/index.cfm/id/9F3A6A1F-C63E-42A3-A19BA9F633A75A61">can be found on the PCS website</a>, and in a branch briefing from your local reps.</p>

<p>A fresh ballot will be necessary due to the new focus of the campaign, and the previous national ballot being held 18 months ago.</p>

<p>The union are pursuing a pay claim for 2013 which includes lifting the pay freeze and 1% cap currently in place, arguing for a minimum 5% or £1200 increase (whichever is greater) and the concept of a living wage to underpin all pay policies.</p>

<p>The current concerns over the 'review' of our terms and conditions will form part of the dispute.</p>

<p>There are also ongoing issues over union facility time, <a href="http://www.pcs.org.uk/en/news_and_events/pcs_comment/index.cfm/id/C00AB256-4E59-4EFF-B39357028F604931">further increases to pension contributions</a> which will be imposed in April 2013, as well as further job cuts and privatisation worries.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Action agreed to end pay freeze and defend working conditions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2012/12/07/action-agreed-to-end-pay-freeze-and-defend-working-conditions/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T10:55:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2012/12/07/action-agreed-to-end-pay-freeze-and-defend-working-conditions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All members are encouraged to <a href="http://www.pcs.org.uk/en/news_and_events/pcs_comment/index.cfm/id/CFB14EC5-BC50-4894-BE33B2DC119F878A">read the latest update on the PCS website</a> regarding the ongoing campaign.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fairer alternative to rip off loans]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2012/12/06/fairer-alternative-to-rip-off-loans/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-06T14:57:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2012/12/06/fairer-alternative-to-rip-off-loans</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As Christmas is approaching, we know a lot of our members will be counting the cost. As we have effectively been in a pay freeze for some years now, and below inflation rises even before that, many PCS members are finding it hard to meet rising costs.</p>

<p>PCS has recently launched a credit union which offers a new alternative to members wishing to save and take out low cost loans, without having to resort to high interest providers on the high street. The credit union is not looking to maximise its profits, like the big banks, but to serve the needs of its members.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>What is it?</h2>

<p>A credit union is owned and run by its members, who legally must have a 'common bond' linking them together. In our case it is membership of a trade union, although it can be based on geography, or by an employer.</p>

<p>The credit unions are regulated by the Financial Services Authority, and operate under a statutory framework. All members of PCS can join, as well as immediate family/partners provided they live in the same household.</p>

<p>PCS members run the union, and ultimate responsibility rests with a board of directors who are members themselves.</p>

<h2>Joining the credit union</h2>

<p>Every member commits to save regularly, with a minimum of £10 per month. Every £1 buys a share in the credit union.</p>

<p>The initial joining fee is £5 which will be deducted from your first deposit. In subsequent years an annual £1 charge will go towards administration costs.</p>

<p>After members have saved for 3 months, they will be eligible to apply for a loan. The amount of money and repayment terms will depend on the period and value of savings, purpose of loan, amount requested and character of the member. Members will initially be able to borrow up to 3 times the amount they have saved.</p>

<p>No arrangement fees are charged on loans and there are no penalties for early repayment. All loans will be protected by life insurance.</p>

<p>All savings are fully protected by the FSA.</p>

<p>You can get more information or <a href="http://www.pcs.org.uk/en/about_pcs/pcs_credit_union/index.cfm">join the credit union on the PCS website</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PCS responds to the chancellor's autumn statement]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2012/12/05/pcs-responds-to-the-chancellors-autumn-statement/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T15:54:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.pcsquorum.org.uk/blog/2012/12/05/pcs-responds-to-the-chancellors-autumn-statement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This afternoon's statement from George Osborne to the House of Commons was met with a <a href="http://www.pcs.org.uk/en/news_and_events/news_centre/index.cfm/id/1E321E19-22DE-4F7B-BC63345A68C226C4">strong response from the PCS general secretary</a> Mark Serwotka:</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote><p>"It is glaringly obvious that not only is the millionaire chancellor George Osborne wildly out of touch with the lives of millions of people in this country, but also that his economic plans are miles off course."</p></blockquote>

<p>For more information on the union's campaigns against the cuts you can visit the PCS website at <a href="http://www.pcs.org.uk/">www.pcs.org.uk</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
